May Memorial Unitarian Universalist Society Records
May Memorial Unitarian Universalist Society Records
- John Fuller, Minister, 1961-1973
  - Photographs of Rev. John Fuller, 4 Sep 1963 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Letters and other material relating to Rev. Fuller's health, 1969-1973; correspondence from Fuller; statements from Fuller and two physicians; church newsletter with message (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Farewell service at James St. Church, 20 Sep 1964; addess by Elizabeth Manwell, "A Reminiscence of Years at May Memorial Church", notes for address by Rev. Fuller "The Heritage We Take", correspondence (Box 6, Folder 5a)
  - Public affairs - school integration, 1964; Public Affairs committee motion in support of Syracuse Board of Ed,; plans for racial integration of Syracuse public schools; President's Report; note on special meeting (Box 6, Folder 5b)
  - Architect's drawing of East Genesee St. church, front end of sanctuary and exterior (Box 6, Folder 5c)
  - Rev. Fuller's annual reports, 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Constition of May Memorial Unitarian Society, Constitution adopted in 1968; discussion of revision items; letter of concern regarding religious education (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Outline of May Memorial Unitarian Society, 1962?; nature of church; history; Sunday program; church groups; community services; minister and staff; publications; facilities (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Pulpit committee, 1967-1968; basic structure plan for R.E.; report of the special committee administration of RE; background information about Syracuse and MMUS; letter from President Verah Johnson to Ron Clark; program for ordination and installation of Ron Clark; notice of settlement to Dept. of Ministry (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1968-1969; Dr. Robert Newman and Rev. Clark; Rev. Manwell and Rev. Clark; reference for Rev. Clark (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Photographs of Rev. Ronald Clark and family (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Sermons by Rev. Clark, The unconditioned; Morality of flower power; Rite of passage; Some thoughts on religious education; Don't rain on my parade; Jack Armstrong syndrome revisited (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence concerning Rev. Clark's resignation, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Evaluation of Ron Clark's ministry by David Koberness, preliminary ministerial fellowship report (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Photographs of G. Abbott and W. McLennon, 1965; opening of box from cornerstone of the James St. Church (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Contents of cornerstone box, Aug 1884; 10 Oct 1965; 13 local newspapers; program from after-church ceremony (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Order of service, drawings of parish house, 7 Jun 1964; undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Drawing of May Memorial Unitarian Church by Joanne Ashley, undated (Box 6, Folder 17a)
  - Memorial to Elizabeth Manwell, St. Lawrence Beacon, Nov 1964 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Material relating to ten stained glass windows at 472 James St. Church, color photographs, letters (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Distribution of various objects from James St. Church, 1973; location of Samuel Joseph May plaque; distribution of various objects (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Notes on MMUS history, letters, notes, memories on MMUS tradition and heritage; information on church history (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Letters in regard to May Memorial Church's tradition and history, 1961; letters from Florida Tracy, Janus B. Lape, Elizabeth Lewis, Helen Burd, Gladys Rowley, Mrs. W.H. Eager; notes on Ann Prescott, Boys' Club, library and processionals; list of church sites and ministers (Box 6, Folder 21a)
  - "Tradition and Heritage of May Memorial Unitarian Church" by John C. Fuller, Jan 1962; lecture delivered to Women's Alliance (Box 6, Folder 21b)
  - [Josephine Gould], 1963; 1967; Employment agreement, announcement of Gould's resignation, Verah Johnson's letter to congregation (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Reports and letters on religious education, 1965-1973; [See outside of folder for full list of contents] (Box 6, Folder 22a)
  - Religious education reports, 1968-1970; calendar for 1968-1969; Youth Education report; Church School report; Children and Youth reports (Box 6, Folder 22b)
  - Meetings and letters on financial crisis, 1969-1970; letters from John Fuller, Mrs. Lawrence Gould, Reginald Manwell, Bairds; minutes of board meetings; minister's report to trustees; graph of income, pledges, expenses; more (see folder for complete list) (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Vanguard Committee, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 23a)
  - Correspondence between John Fuller and Board of Trustees relating to his resignation, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - List of services, 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Consensus meetings, 1 Apr 1973; preliminary report (Box 6, Folder 25a)
  - Documents surrounding John Fuller's new placement, Apr 1973; statement by John Fuller; Board of Trustee's response; announcement of resignation; announcement of farewell party (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence concerning the microfilms of the Samuel J. May letters with Cornell Library, 1965-1966; letters to/from Howard Applegate, George Abbot, John H. Chamberlain, William H. Pease, George Healey, Rev. John Fuller, M. Slagle; list of church records (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Memorial service for Rev. John Channing Fuller, Dec 1974; program for memorial service; clippings (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - [Photograph of] Rick Masten and congregation in back yard, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Canvass materials, 1968-1971; pledge appeals; fellowship dinner invitiation and program; proposal for associate minister; canvass brochure and letter (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Sermons and addresses by other ministers and friends of the church, 1962; 1968,; 1973; Paul Meadows, Search for Meaning; Dr. Alexander Patterson, Peter Meets Paul; Harriette Robinson, Loneliness and Aloneness; John Wilkinson III, The Meaning of Religion (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Typed manuscript by Charles D'Aniello, "Samuel Joseph May: Abolitionist", undated (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Beyond the Ego, sermon by Isabel Aird, 10 Sep 1967 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - The Remarkable Mr. May, typed sermon by Cathy Covert, 13 Feb 1962 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Publications from the UUA authored by Elizabeth Manwell, 1964; undated; The first of life (52pp); Always growing (8pp) (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - [Josephine Gould], 1964; undated; UUA publication, "A guide to the use of conversations with children"; 8x10 black and white photograph of Jo Gould and children; science series, "What is Real?"; 3x5 color photo of Elizabeth Walsh, Jo Gould, Doug Temple (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Filmstrip and text, "A child grows in the church", 1968; text by Josephine Gould, photographs by Bob Burdick, UUA; thank you letter from Jo Gould (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Introducing May Memorial membership folder, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Reports on Baby Fold study, 1962; report of committee; letters from parents (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Reports on organ at the Genesee St. Church, 1962-1963; reports of building administration committee; Board notes; report of music committee; letter from Howland Auchincloss to Henry D. Merteus (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Analysis of DRE job, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Commission study groups, 1962; The free church in a changing world; Education and liberal religions; Religion and the arts; Ethics and social action; report on world religion and outreach (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Fundraising events, 1962; 1970-1971; report on special activities committee; May Fair materials; All Church Fair; international film festival; book sale; Friday film festival (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Photos and drawings of James St. Church, 1963; 1965; photos and drawings of church; photos and negatives from razing of the church (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Letter from program council regarding civil rights groups holding meetings at MMUS, 1 Oct 1963 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Downtown Thanksgiving service, 1963-1964; order of service; news clipping; photo John Fuller (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Annual meeting programs and reports, 1962-1965; annual dinners and meetings (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Membership activities, 1962-1967; membership lists; "Introducing May Memorial" brochure; church directory; policy for changing membership status; area chairs and responsibilities; mailing on "Good Neighbor Policy" (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Finance concerns, 1964-1969; canvass literature; letters to Board of Trustees, congregation; minister's report to trustees; board minutes; budget and expenditures; cost estimates, solicitation for a solvent society (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - New hymnal, 1965; introductory letter; sample hymns (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Petition and vote [on] teen board member, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Annual meeting programs and reports, 1966-1974; annual dinners and meetings (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Statement by ICF to NYS constitutional convention, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Papers on JCF work with conscientious objectors, 1967-1969; UUSC letter; conscientious objector program and resolutions; Andrew Blauvelt letter (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Summer church programs, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Operating manual committees, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Letter to Board of Education, Syracuse, endorsing campus plan, undated (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Summary by E. Rosebrugh, "Religion and the tax-supported school", undated (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - Fuller vs. IRS, 1970; correspondence (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Charman art exhibit, May 1971 (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - Public affairs committee activities, 1961-1965; letter to Warren B. Walsh; letters to congregation; committee reports and recommendations; printed material (see front of folder for complete list of contents) (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - Scattered site public housing committee, 1965; letters; survey of public housing residents; study; final presentation (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - Letters, D. Koberness, WSYR, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - Church council, 1966-1968 (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - Memorial service for Elizabeth Lewis, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - Pledge letter to congregation, 29 Jan 1973 (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - Selected Fuller sermons, 1964-1965; Is it a matter of the heart?; Why I am a Unitarian; The religion we built it for (Box 6, Folder 67)